# Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair

E-mail:ngopala<br/>2@jhu.edu  $Telephone\ number:\ +1\text{-}667\text{-}212\text{-}9785$ <br/>  $Address:\ 3501$  Saint Paul Street, Apt 935, Baltimore, MD, USA

Social Networks: 
in 

©

#### Research Interests

I work on problems in Computer Vision. My research areas include deep generative modelling with a special emphasis on plug and play models and efficient architectures for generation, enabling training and inference of generative models on low-compute resources.

## Education

# Ph.D candidate in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Johns Hopkins University January 2021 - Present

Advisor: Dr Vishal Patel

CGPA: 3.96/4.0

Research focused on deep generative modelling, low compute networks and low-level vision

### **Bachelors in Electrical Engineering**

Indian Institute of technology, Madras July 2015 - July 2020

B. Tech and M. tech dual degree program CGPA: 9.0/10.0

M. Tech Thesis: Unconstrained dual-lens deblurring using deep networks

#### **Publications**

Highlights: 7 first-authored accepted papers, 2 first-authored accepted paper in CVPR '23, ICCV '23

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Anoop Cherian, Suhas Lohit, Toshi Akino, Ye Wang, Vishal M Patel, Tim Marks, Steered Diffusion: A Generalized Framework for Plug-and-Play Conditional Face Synthesis, Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF international conference on computer vision, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Vishal Patel, Unite and Conquer: Cross Dataset Multimodal Synthesis using Diffusion Models, *Proceedings of the IEEE conference on computer vision and pattern recognition*, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, AT-DDPM: Restoring Faces degraded by Atmospheric Turbulence using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models, *IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)*, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Vishal Patel, T2V-DDPM: Thermal to Visible Face Translation using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models, *IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face & Gesture Recognition*, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, A comparison of different atmospheric turbulence simulation methods for image restoration, *IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)*, 2022

Malsha Perera, **Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair**, Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Vishal Patel, SAR Despeckling using a Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Model, *IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters*, 2023

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Rajeev Yasarla, Vishal Patel, NBD-GAP: Non-Blind Image Deblurring Without Clean Target Images, *IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP)*, 2022

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Rajeev Yasarla Vishal Patel, Confidence Guided Network For Atmospheric Turbulence Mitigation, IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2021

Mahesh Mohan MR, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, AN Rajagopalan, Deep Dynamic Scene Deblurring for Unconstrained Dual-Lens Cameras, IEEE Transacations in Image Processing (TIP) 2021

Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Kangfu Mei, Vishal Patel, Bi-Noising Diffusion: Towards Conditional Diffusion Models with Generative Restoration Priors, Under review 2023

Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Vishal Patel, Diffuse-Denoise-Count: Accurate Crowd-Counting with Diffusion Models, Under review 2023

Yasiru Ranasinghe, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Wele Gedara Chaminda Bandara, Vishal M Patel, DDPM-CD: Remote Sensing Change Detection using Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models, Under review 2023

Jay N Paranjape, Nithin Gopalakrishnan Nair, Shameema Sikder, S Swaroop Vedula, Vishal M Patel, Adaptivesam: Towards efficient tuning of sam for surgical scene segmentation, Under review 2023

# Professional Experience

Adobe Inc. Mistubishi Electric Research Labs **Indian Space Research Organization** VIU Lab, JHU IPCV Lab, IIT Madras

May 2022 - August 2023 May 2022 - August 2023 November 2016 - January 2016 Sept 2022 - Present May 2019- August 2020

## Portfolio of most relevant projects

Adobe Firefly

Adobe's Image generation model

May 2023 - Present Seattle, USA

• Devloping an Interactive Image Editing Algorithm

BRIAR. IARPA's face recognition program August 2021 - Present Baltimore, USA

Developing a robust large-scale face recognition framework as part of the BRIAR program.

LIGO data analysis

January 2019 - May 2019 Chennai, India

UC Berkeley

**EMISAT** 

• Worked on the Signal Processing side of analyzing data capture for the LIGO project

India's signal detection Satellite

May 2017- July 2017

Bangalore, India

Developed a signal analyzer for undersampled signal detection for EMISAT

#### Awards and Scholastic Achievements

- All India Rank 454 in Joint Engineering Entrance (Advanced) 2015 from 1.5 million candidates.
- State rank 4 in KEAM 2015 from over 200,000 candidates.

- $\bullet$  Awarded certificate for being among the top 0.1% in AISSCE 2015 by Central Board of Secondary Education, India.
- Awarded Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana Scholarship 2014, by the Government of India, given to top 1000 from 300,000 candidates to pursure study in Sciences.
- All India Topper in NPTEL Analog Electronic Systems, 2018.

# Technical skills

Invited Reviewer: PAMI

| Programming Languages/Tools<br>Academic | C, C++, Python, SQL, Verilog, VHDL<br>Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Digital Electronics, Analog Electronics |
|---|---|
| Services                                |   |
| National Service Scheme 2015            | Worked on Enriching Malayalam Wikipedia   |
| National Service Scheme 2016            | Worked on Suyam Project, aimed at preliminary education<br>for students in rural villages in India                              |
| Invited Reviewer: ICCV 23'              | The International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)  |
| Invited Reviewer: CVPR 23'              | IEEE / CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Con-   |
| Invited Reviewer: WACV 24'              |   |
|   | 1   |

Vision (CVPR)

gence(TPAMI)

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelli-